A Guide to the Receipts for laws of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1786-1867
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Receipts for laws of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1786-1867
The Library of Virginia
36145
5.2 cu. ft. (12 boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of Commonwealth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information unavailable.
Biographical Information
The Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth has evolved from early colonial times when there existed a Secretary of the Colony. Thomas Nelson held the position of the first Secretary of Virginia in 1776. Early Secretaries were elected by the public. An Act of the General Assembly in 1920 changed the election to a joint vote of the General Assembly. In a 1930 Act the duties of the Secretary were redefined with the Secretary of the Commonwealth serving as the ex officio secretary of the Governor, as custodian of many official State records, and as keeper of the Greater and Lesser Seals of the Commonwealth. The office of the Secretary has gradually acquired other functions, such as: service of out-of-state civil process; appointment and regulation of notaries public; and registration and oversight of lobbyists. The Office became a gubernatorial appointment subsequent to a 1958 Act of the Assembly. The Secretary of the Commonwealth is under the jurisdiction of the Governor's Office. The Secretary is appointed by the Governor for a term of four years. Currently the Secretary of the Commonwealth is responsible for gubernatorial appointments, clemency and restoration of civil rights requests and extraditions. Additional activities include: serving as ex officio Secretary to the Governor; serving as keeper of the seals of the Commonwealth; compiling and publishing the annual Blue Book; commissioning and regulating notary publics, including the publication of a Notary Handbook and conduct of disciplinary hearings; promulgating the lobbying disclosure requirements, registration of lobbyists, and recording of lobbying reports; servicing the civil process of out-of-state defendants and other parties; and authenticating and certifying the records of the courts and of any state agency.
Scope and Content
Receipts, 1786-1867, from court clerks for session acts, codes, statutes at large, etc., distributed by the Secretary of the Commonwealth of Virginia. The receipts are arranged by year and grouped together by name of the person who delivered the acts and laws to the clerks. Included are receipts, lists of counties in a district, notebooks containing signed receipts from county clerks, and notebooks on mileage travelled. Also included is some correspondence. Of note are the applications for employment, 1823, sent to the Governor. The applications consist of letters from people wanting to do the job of delivering the laws and letters of recommendation for them.
The following is a list of the districts and the counties included in each district. Often included in the records were lists naming the district and counties for each person delivering the materials. These lists were used to create the district list below, though there might be some discrepancies over the years as districts changed.
District No. 1 included the counties Accomack, Amelia, Brunswick, Chesterfield, Dinwiddie, Greensville, Isle of Wight, Lunenburg, Mecklenburg, Nansemond, Norfolk (City and County), Northampton, Nottoway, Prince George, Princess Anne, Southampton, Sussex, and Surry; and Petersburg. District No. 2 included the counties of Berkeley, Caroline, Clarke, Culpeper, Fairfax, Fauquier, Frederick, Hampshire, Hardy, Hanover, Jefferson, Loudoun, Morgan, Page, Pendleton, Pocahontas, Prince William, Rapphannock, Shenandoah, Spotsylvania, Stafford, and Warren; and Fredericksburg and Winchester. District No. 3 included the counties of Bedford, Botetourt, Buckingham, Campbell, Charlotte, Cumberland, Floyd, Franklin, Giles, Grayson, Halifax, Henry, Lee, Mercer, Patrick, Montgomery, Pittsylvania, Powhatan, Prince Edward, Pulaksi, Russell, Scott, Smyth, Tazewell, Washington, and Wythe; and Lynchburg and Roanoke. District No. 4 included the counties Albemarle, Alleghany, Amherst, Augusta, Bath, Cabell, Fayette, Fluvanna, Goochland, Greenbrier, Jackson, Kanawha, Logan, Mason, Monroe, Nelson, and Rockbridge. District No. 5 included the counties of Charles City, Elizabeth City, Essex, Gloucester, James City, Henrico, King and Queen, King George, King William, Lancaster, Mathews, Middlesex, New Kent, Northumberland, Richmond (City and County), Warwick, Westmoreland, and York; and Williamsburg. District No. 6 included the counties of Braxton Brooke, Greene, Harrison, Lewis, Louisa, Madison, Marshall, Monongalia, Orange, Ohio, Preston, Randolph, Rockingham, Tyler, and Wood; and Wheeling. In the 1850-1860s a few new districts appears. District No. 7 included the counties of Alleghany, Braxton, Clay, Greenbrier, Kanawha Jackson, Mason, Nicholas, Pocahontas, Webster; and Roanoke. District No. 9 included the counties of Boone, Cabell, Fayette, Logan, Mercer, Monroe, Putnam, Raleigh, Wayne, and Wyoming.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- 1786, Archibald Blair (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1800, John Atkinson [Dist. No. 3] (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1800, Aylite Buckner [Dist. No. 1] (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1800, Charles Carter [Dist. No. 5] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1800, Joseph Childress [Dist. No. 3] (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1800, John Elliot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1800, John Gunn [Dist. No. 5] (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1800, James Laughlin (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1800, John Moore (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1801, John Atkinson (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 1801, Samuel Coleman (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1801, John Gunn [Dist. No. 5] (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1801, Nathaniel Holoman [Dist. No. 1] (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 1801, John McKenny (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1801, Isaac Taylor (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 1802, John Atkinson [Dist. No. 3] (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 1802, Thomas Eldridge (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 1802, John Gunn [Dist. No. 5] (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 1802, Nathaniel Holoman [Dist. No. 1] (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 1802, Peter Price (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 1803, John Atkinson [Dist. No. 3] (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 1803, Robinson Lord [Dist. No. 2] (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 1803, John Gunn [Dist. No. 5] (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 1803, Nathaniel Holoman [Dist. No. 2] (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 1803, Peter Price (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 1804, Robinson Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 1809 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 1810, John Gunn, Robinson Lord, and Bernard Reynolds (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 1813, [Dist. No. 1] (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1819, Bernard Reynolds [Dist. No. 3] (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 1820, John Jacobs (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 1820, John Quicksall [Dist. No. 3] (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1820, John H. Pettus [Dist. No. 2] (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1820, Norborne Ratcliffe [Dist. No. 6] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 1820, Bernard Reynolds (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 1822, John Ford (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 1822, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 1822, John P. Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 1823, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 1823, Applications for employment (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 1823 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 1824, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 1824, John P. Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 1824-1825, Tarlton H. Ford [Dist. No. 3] (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 1825, John Ford (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 1825, Tarleton H. Ford [Dist. No. 3] (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 1825, Erastus Gilbert [Dist. No. 1] (Box 4, Folder 2)
- 1826, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 4, Folder 3)
- 1826, Tarlton H. Ford [Dist. No. 3] (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 1826, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 1827, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 4, Folder 6)
- 1827, Tarlton H. Ford [Dist. No. 3] (Box 4, Folder 7)
- 1827, James W. Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 4, Folder 8)
- 1827, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 4, Folder 9)
- 1827, Barton Smoot [Mason Co.] (Box 4, Folder 10)
- 1828, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 1828, Tarlton H. Ford [Dist. No. 3] (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 1828, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 4, Folder 13)
- 1828, James W. Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 4, Folder 14)
- 1828, Receipt for a map [Henrico Co.] (Box 4, Folder 15)
- 1829, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 4, Folder 16)
- 1829, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 4, Folder 17)
- 1829, Tarlton H. Ford [Dist. No. 3] (Box 4, Folder 18)
- 1829, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 4, Folder 19)
- 1829, James W. Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 4, Folder 20)
- 1829, List of General Assembly members (Box 4, Folder 21)
- 1830, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 4, Folder 22)
- 1830, James W. Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 4, Folder 23)
- 1831, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 5, Folder 1)
- 1831, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 5, Folder 2)
- 1831, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 5, Folder 3)
- 1831, James W. Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 5, Folder 4)
- 1831, Charles S. McCoull [Dist. No. 3] (Box 5, Folder 5)
- 1831, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 5, Folder 6)
- 1832, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 5, Folder 7)
- 1832, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 5, Folder 8)
- 1832, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 5, Folder 9)
- 1832, James W. Lord [Dist. No. 1] (Box 5, Folder 10)
- 1832, Charles S. McCoull [Dist. No. 3] (Box 5, Folder 11)
- 1832, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 5, Folder 12)
- 1833, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 5, Folder 13)
- 1833, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 5, Folder 14)
- 1833, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 5, Folder 15)
- 1833, Charles S. McCoull [Dist. No. 3] (Box 5, Folder 16)
- 1833-1834, James A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 5, Folder 17)
- 1833-1834, Charles S. McCoull [Dist. No. 3] (Box 5, Folder 18)
- 1833, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 5, Folder 19)
- 1834, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 5, Folder 20)
- 1834, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 5, Folder 21)
- 1834, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 6, Folder 1)
- 1834, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 1834, Charles S. McCoull [Dist. No. 3] (Box 6, Folder 3)
- 1834, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 6, Folder 4)
- 1835, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 6, Folder 5)
- 1835, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 6, Folder 6)
- 1835, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 6, Folder 7)
- 1835, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 6, Folder 8)
- 1835, Charles S. McCoull [Dist. No. 3] (Box 6, Folder 9)
- 1835, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 6, Folder 10)
- 1836, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 6, Folder 11)
- 1836, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 6, Folder 12)
- 1836, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 6, Folder 13)
- 1836, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 6, Folder 14)
- 1836, Charles S. McCoull [Dist. No. 3] (Box 6, Folder 15)
- 1837, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 1837, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 6, Folder 17)
- 1837, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 6, Folder 18)
- 1837, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 6, Folder 19)
- 1837, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 6, Folder 20)
- 1837, Charles S. McCoull [Dist. No. 3] (Box 6, Folder 21)
- 1838, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 6, Folder 22)
- 1838, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 6, Folder 23)
- 1838, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 7, Folder 1)
- 1838, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 7, Folder 2)
- 1838, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 7, Folder 3)
- 1839, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 7, Folder 4)
- 1839, Hudson Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 7, Folder 5)
- 1839, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 7, Folder 6)
- 1839, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 7, Folder 7)
- 1839, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 7, Folder 8)
- 1839, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 7, Folder 9)
- 1840, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 7, Folder 10)
- 1840, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 7, Folder 11)
- 1840, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 7, Folder 12)
- 1840, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 7, Folder 13)
- 1841, Ryland Ford [Dist. No. 4-5] (Box 7, Folder 14)
- 1841, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 7, Folder 15)
- 1841, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 7, Folder 16)
- 1841, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 7, Folder 17)
- 1842, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 8, Folder 1)
- 1842, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 8, Folder 2)
- 1842, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 8, Folder 3)
- 1842, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 8, Folder 4)
- 1842, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 8, Folder 5)
- 1842, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 8, Folder 6)
- 1843, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 8, Folder 7)
- 1843, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 8, Folder 8)
- 1843, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 8, Folder 9)
- 1843, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 8, Folder 10)
- 1843, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 8, Folder 11)
- 1844, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 8, Folder 12)
- 1844, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 8, Folder 13)
- 1844, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 8, Folder 14)
- 1844, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 8, Folder 15)
- 1844, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 8, Folder 16)
- 1844, Barton Smoot [Dist. No. 4] (Box 8, Folder 17)
- 1845, James A. Echo [Dist. No. 1] (Box 8, Folder 18)
- 1845, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 8, Folder 19)
- 1845, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 8, Folder 20)
- 1845, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 8, Folder 21)
- 1845, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 9, Folder 1)
- 1845, Barton Smoot (Box 9, Folder 2)
- 1845, William G. Allen [Dist. No. 4] (Box 9, Folder 3)
- 1846, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 9, Folder 4)
- 1846, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 9, Folder 5)
- 1846, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 9, Folder 6)
- 1846, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 9, Folder 7)
- 1846, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 9, Folder 8)
- 1847, William Allan [Dist. No. 4] (Box 9, Folder 9)
- 1847, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 9, Folder 10)
- 1847, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 9, Folder 11)
- 1847, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 9, Folder 12)
- 1847, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 9, Folder 13)
- 1847, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 9, Folder 14)
- 1848, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 9, Folder 15)
- 1848, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 9, Folder 16)
- 1848, William G. Allan [Dist. No. 4] (Box 10, Folder 1)
- 1848, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 10, Folder 2)
- 1848, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 10, Folder 3)
- 1848, William Hutchison [Dist. No. 6] (Box 10, Folder 4)
- 1849, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 10, Folder 5)
- 1849, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 10, Folder 6)
- 1849, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 10, Folder 7)
- 1849, Thomas Gordon [Dist. No. 3] (Box 10, Folder 8)
- 1849, Brooke Co. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- 1850, William E. Broiler [Dist. No. 4] (Box 10, Folder 10)
- 1850, William Cackley [Dist. No. 4] (Box 10, Folder 11)
- 1850, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 5] (Box 10, Folder 12)
- 1850, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 1] (Box 10, Folder 13)
- 1850, Dist. No. 5 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- 1850, Accomack-Buckingham Counties (Box 10, Folder 15)
- 1850, Campbell-Greensville Counties (Box 10, Folder 16)
- 1850, Halifax-Jefferson Counties (Box 10, Folder 17)
- 1850, Kanawha-Morgan Counties (Box 10, Folder 18)
- 1850, Nansemond-Pulaski Counties (Box 11, Folder 1)
- 1850, Raleigh-Sussex Counties (Box 11, Folder 2)
- 1850, Taylor-York Counties (Box 11, Folder 3)
- 1850, Multiple counties (Box 11, Folder 4)
- 1851, John Ford [Dist. No. 2] (Box 11, Folder 5)
- 1851 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- 1852, William Cacksley [Dist. No. 7] (Box 11, Folder 7)
- 1859-1863 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- 1860, Josiah Blackburn [Dist. No. 7] (Box 11, Folder 9)
- 1860, John A. Eacho [Dist. No. 2] (Box 11, Folder 10)
- 1860, Andrew H. Ford [Dist. No. 4] (Box 11, Folder 11)
- 1860, Henry Ford [Dist. No. 9] (Box 11, Folder 12)
- 1860, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 1] (Box 11, Folder 13)
- 1860, Spotswood Ford [Dist. No. 1] (Box 11, Folder 14)
- 1860, John N. Gordon [Dist. No 3 and 6] (Box 11, Folder 15)
- 1860, J.G. Moss [Dist. No. 5] (Box 12, Folder 1)
- 1861, Josiah Blackburn [Dist. No. 7] (Box 12, Folder 2)
- 1861, Valentine Brown (Box 12, Folder 3)
- 1861, Hudson B. Ford [Dist. No. 1] (Box 12, Folder 4)
- 1861, Spotswood Ford [Dist. No. 3] (Box 12, Folder 5)
- 1861, Daniel M. Gordon (Box 12, Folder 6)
- 1861, John N. Gordon (Box 12, Folder 7)
- 1861, J.D. Moore (Box 12, Folder 8)
- 1861, J.G. Moss (Box 12, Folder 9)
- 1861, John J. Palmer (Box 12, Folder 10)
- 1861, R.L. Wigglesworth [Dist. No. 5] (Box 12, Folder 11)
- 1862, Josiah Blackburn (Box 12, Folder 12)
- 1862, John N. Gordon [Dist. No. 6] (Box 12, Folder 13)
- 1862, John J. Palmer (Box 12, Folder 14)
- 1864, William F. Gordon (Box 12, Folder 15)
- 1866, Andrew Ford (Box 12, Folder 16)
- 1867, S. Ford (Box 12, Folder 17)